Everyone.
الجميع.
Since Mr. Lan has handed over the Examiner Seal,
منذ أن سلم السيد لان ختم الممتحن ،
the examination will continue.
سيستمر الفحص.
I'll draw
سأرسم
the question of the examination
سؤال الامتحان
on behalf of the Ministry of Rites.
نيابة عن وزارة الطقوس.
Wait.
انتظر.
What's happening?
ماذا يحدث؟
Considering
مع مراعاة
everyone in the Ministry of Rites is under Mr. Lan's command.
كل شخص في وزارة الطقوس تحت قيادة السيد لان.
There still might be fraud
لا يزال هناك احتيال
if they act on his orders.
إذا كانوا يتصرفون بناءً على أوامره.
What do you want?
ماذا تريد؟
If the examination is to continue,
إذا كان الفحص سيستمر ،
it must be guaranteed
يجب أن تكون مضمونة
that there's no possibility of fraud,
أنه لا يوجد احتمال للاحتيال ،
especially in the drawing process
خاصة في عملية الرسم
which has to be done impartially
الذي يجب أن يتم بحيادية
with no possibility of any kind of interference.
مع عدم وجود أي احتمال من أي نوع من التدخل.
Everyone.
الجميع.
If you don't trust us,
إذا كنت لا تثق بنا ،
you can elect someone to draw the question.
يمكنك اختيار شخص ما لرسم السؤال.
The three ministers and everyone in the Ministry of Rites
الوزراء الثلاثة والجميع في وزارة الطقوس
have no objection.
ليس لديهم اعتراض.
We've just discussed it.
لقد ناقشناها للتو.
If we choose an examinee to draw the question,
إذا اخترنا ممتحنًا لرسم السؤال ،
it'll still be hardly convincing.
سيظل مقنعًا بصعوبة.
How about this,
وماذا عن هذا،
we'll choose an irrelevant person
سنختار شخصًا غير ذي صلة
to draw the topic blindfolded to be fair.
لرسم الموضوع معصوب العينين ليكون عادلاً.
Who do you want to choose?
من تريد أن تختار؟
The old man
الرجل العجوز
who sweeps the courtyard.
الذي كانس الفناء.
He isn't an official.
إنه ليس مسؤولاً.
He doesn't have a stake in this matter.
ليس لديه مصلحة في هذا الأمر.
Mr. Yang?
السيد.  أيّ؟
=A League of Nobleman=
= عصبة النبلاء =
=Episode 18=
= الحلقة 18 =
(The 20th Year of Yongxuan)
(السنة العشرون ليونغ شوان)
(Rule the Country by Virtue)
(حكم البلاد بالفضيلة)
Rule the Country by Virtue.
حكم البلاد بالفضيلة.
The question was
كان السؤال
written by Mr. Liu.
كتبه السيد ليو.
Write an essay
اكتب مقالاً
on the topic of
حول موضوع
"ruling the country by virtue".
"حكم البلاد بالفضيلة".
The examination starts now.
يبدأ الفحص الآن.
(Guiyou)
(جويو)
(Xinmao)
(إكسينماو)
(Lan Jue)
(لان جو)
(The two prophecies of Mr. Jinghu)
(نبوأتان للسيد جينغو)
(directly refer to the imperial examination,)
(الرجوع مباشرة إلى الامتحان الإمبراطوري ،)
(which also involved Mr. Lan.)
(والتي تضمنت أيضًا السيد لان).
(What's his purpose?)
(ما هو هدفه؟)
(Chen Zishang)
(تشين زيشانغ)
(Enemy Prophecy)
(نبوءة العدو)
(Mr. Jinghu)
(السيد جينغو)
(Why didn't Chen Zishang)
(لماذا لم تشن زيشانغ)
(show up for the exam?)
(تحضر للامتحان؟)
(Guiyou)
(جويو)
(Seems that I must find Mr. Jinghu as soon as possible.)
(يبدو أنه يجب أن أجد السيد جينغو في أقرب وقت ممكن.)
Maybe I should
ربما ينبغي ان
start with Chen Zishang.
ابدأ مع Chen Zishang.
(Every king desires to be...)
(كل ملك يرغب في أن يكون ...)
(Renshen)
(رينشن)
(The previous dynasties...)
(السلالات السابقة ...)
(Yiwei)
(يوي)
(Renwu)
(رينو)
Zhang.
تشانغ.
(Rule the Country by Virtue)
(حكم البلاد بالفضيلة)
Did it only take you one day to finish the essay?
هل استغرق الأمر منك يومًا واحدًا لإنهاء المقال؟
I finished it very early.
انتهيت من ذلك في وقت مبكر جدا.
(Suzhou Government, Jiangnan County Ma Lian, Rule the Country by Virtue)
(حكومة سوتشو ، مقاطعة جيانغنان ما ليان ، حكم البلد بالفضيلة)
Sir!
سيد!
Have some snacks, sir!
تناول بعض الوجبات الخفيفة يا سيدي!
(Exam Hall)
(قاعة الامتحان)
Let's go now.
دعنا نذهب الان.
I don't want to stay here any longer.
لا أريد البقاء هنا لفترة أطول.
Where's the carriage?
أين العربة؟
Sir.
سيد.
It's at the gate.
إنه عند البوابة.
Please move your steps.
يرجى تحريك خطواتك.
You useless thing!
أنت شيء عديم الفائدة!
Why did you park it there? It's too far!
لماذا أوقفته هناك؟  انه بعيد جدا!
Sir, please don't be mad.
سيدي ، من فضلك لا تغضب.
The guards of Exam Hall
حراس قاعة الامتحان
wouldn't let us park here.
لن تسمح لنا بركن سيارتك هنا.
Did you tell them my name?
هل قلت لهم اسمي؟
I did.
فعلتُ.
Dogs are more capable than you.
الكلاب أكثر قدرة منك.
Get the carriage here now!
احصل على العربة هنا الآن!
Yes, yes.
نعم نعم.
Yes.
نعم.
What are you looking at?
الى ماذا تنظرين؟
(Zhang from Xichuan)
(Zhang from Xichuan)
Is this Chen Zishang's residence?
هل هذا مقر إقامة تشن زيشانغ؟
Chen Zishang.
تشن زيشانغ.
Mr. Lan, you will be punished for dereliction of duty.
سيد لان ، ستتم معاقبتك على التقصير في أداء الواجب.
You've made a big noise.
لقد أحدثت ضجة كبيرة.
Even if you ask to be imprisoned,
حتى لو طلبت أن تسجن ،
it's still hard to justify yourself in front of the Emperor
لا يزال من الصعب تبرير نفسك أمام الإمبراطور
as the chief examiner.
بصفته رئيس الممتحنين.
(Why would Mr. Jinghu)
(لماذا السيد جينغو)
(interfere with the examination?)
(تتداخل مع الفحص؟)
(Is the acrostic	poetry only for)
(هو الشعر الافقى فقط ل)
(slandering me for accepting bribes?)
(الافتراء عليّ لقبول الرشاوى؟)
(Common people may)
(يجوز لعامة الناس)
(come out on top.)
(تأتي على رأس القائمة.)
Go in there.
اذهب الى هناك.
Mr. Lan.
السيد.  لان.
♪The cows are awake and want to graze♪
الأبقار مستيقظة وتريد الرعي ♪
♪Excellent grass is in the south♪
عشب ممتاز في الجنوب ♪
Time to eat.
وقت الطعام.
Mr. Lan.
السيد.  لان.
Are you gonna eat?
هل ستأكل؟
If you don't eat,
إذا كنت لا تأكل ،
I'll eat yours, too.
أنا سوف آكل لك أيضا.
I'm a little hungry.
أنا جائع قليلا.
Leave it there.
اتركه هناك.
I...
أنا...
I'll eat later.
سوف آكل لاحقا.
Hurry up.
أسرع - بسرعة.
It will get cold soon.
ستبرد قريبا.
You actually brought food
لقد أحضرت الطعام بالفعل
to the Judicial Prison.
إلى السجن العدلي.
I have to thank you for that.
يجب أن أشكرك على ذلك.
Earlier, you recommended me
في وقت سابق ، أوصيتني
for the job in the case archive.
للوظيفة في أرشيف الحالة.
That's how I made the acquaintance with the jailer here.
هكذا تعرفت على السجان هنا.
Thanks to him,
بفضله،
I'm here imprisoned with you.
أنا هنا مسجون معك.
I asked to be put in prison
طلبت أن يوضع في السجن
to stabilize the situation of the examination,
لتحقيق الاستقرار في حالة الفحص ،
but why are you here?
لكن لماذا انت هنا
Chen Zishang is dead.
تشن زيشانغ مات.
What?
ماذا؟
I felt
شعرت
it was strange that Chen didn't show up
كان من الغريب أن تشين لم يظهر
for the exam.
للامتحان.
Therefore,
لذلك،
I handed in my exam paper early
سلمت ورقة الامتحان الخاصة بي في وقت مبكر
and went to his house.
وذهب الى بيته.
I found Chen Zishang
لقد وجدت Chen Zishang
lying dead by the well
ممددا على البئر
for a while.
لفترة وجيزة.
(Looks like)
(يشبه)
(he fell to his death while bathing.)
(سقط حتى وفاته أثناء الاستحمام).
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
there is something suspicious about it.
هناك شيء مريب حيال ذلك.
The strange thing is
الشيء الغريب هو
that if you fall while bathing,
أنه إذا سقطت أثناء الاستحمام ،
your body will instinctively arch up
سوف يتقوس جسمك غريزيًا
to protect your head and neck
لحماية رأسك ورقبتك
by landing on your hips and waist first,
عن طريق الهبوط على وركيك وخصرك أولاً ،
but there are no injuries
لكن لا توجد اصابات
on Chen Zishang's waist, back and hips,
على الخصر والظهر والوركين تشين زيشانغ ،
which means he already lost the ability to react
مما يعني أنه فقد بالفعل القدرة على الرد
when he fell.
عندما سقط.
So,
لذا،
I think the murderer killed him first,
أعتقد أن القاتل قتله أولاً ،
then faked the bathing scene
ثم زيف مشهد الاستحمام
and made him pose like he was tripped up and fell.
وجعله يقف كما لو أنه تعثر وسقط.
Unfortunately,
للأسف،
the scene was washed by the rain
تم غسل المشهد بالمطر
and most of the traces
ومعظم الآثار
were ruined.
دمروا.
Who do you think
من تظن
the killer might be?
قد يكون القاتل؟
I don't know yet.
أنا لا أعرف حتى الآن.
But
لكن
I found other clues.
لقد وجدت أدلة أخرى.
I went into Chen Zishang's room
ذهبت إلى غرفة Chen Zishang
and found that he had packed
ووجد أنه كان قد حزم أمتعة
all his luggage.
كل أمتعته.
It didn't look like
لا يبدو
he was going to Exam Hall,
كان ذاهبًا إلى قاعة الامتحانات ،
but rather like he was going far away.
بل بالأحرى وكأنه كان ذاهبًا بعيدًا.
I felt confused
شعرت بالحيرة
and looked through his bookcase.
ونظر من خلال خزانة كتبه.
There were some drafts in there
كان هناك بعض المسودات هناك
besides books.
بجانب الكتب.
(Rule the Country by Virtue)
(حكم البلاد بالفضيلة)
Chen Zishang's draft
مشروع تشن Zishang
is exactly the same as Ma Lian's answer sheet.
هي بالضبط نفس ورقة إجابة Ma Lian.
Is the topic of the examination
هو موضوع الامتحان
"Rule the Country by Virtue"?
"حكم البلاد بالفضيلة"؟
How do you know it?
كيف تعرف ذلك؟
During the last two days in prison,
خلال اليومين الأخيرين في السجن ،
I pondered Mr. Jinghu's
فكرت في السيد جينغو
prophetic poem.
قصيدة نبوية.
There is something
يوجد شيء
hidden in it.
مخبأة فيه.
Do you have a brush and paper?
هل لديك فرشاة و ورق؟
Common people may come out on top.
قد يأتي عامة الناس في المقدمة.
Remove the radical "Ren" from the character "Si",
إزالة الراديكالية "Ren" من شخصية "Si" ،
and it will be the character "Yi" left.
وستكون شخصية "يي" اليسار.
Traveling the same journey can clear one's mind.
السفر في نفس الرحلة يمكن أن يصفي ذهن المرء.
Combine the characters "Xing", "Xin", and "Mu",
اجمع بين الأحرف "Xing" و "Xin" و "Mu" ،
and it will be the character "De".
وستكون شخصية "دي".
If there is not enough gold inlaid with jade.
إذا لم يكن هناك ما يكفي من الذهب المطعمة باليشم.
The character "Ding" without the radical "Jin"
شخصية "دينغ" بدون الراديكالية "جين".
becomes the character "Ding".
تصبح شخصية "دينغ".
The borderland can't be ruled and the people will be disappointed.
لا يمكن الحكم على الحدود وسيصاب الناس بخيبة أمل.
The first half of this line
النصف الأول من هذا الخط
means there is no borderland to rule.
يعني أنه لا توجد منطقة حدودية للحكم.
The character "Yu"
شخصية "يو"
without the radical "Tu"
بدون الراديكالية "Tu"
is the character "Huo".
هي شخصية "Huo".
The character "Kou" is a square.
الحرف "كو" مربع.
Combine these two characters,
اجمع بين هذين الحرفين ،
and it will be the character "Guo".
وستكون شخصية "Guo".
On the surface,
على السطح،
this poem satirizes the fraud of the imperial examination,
هذه القصيدة تسخر من تزوير الامتحان الإمبراطوري ،
but if you
ولكن إذا كنت
break down the poem,
تحطيم القصيدة ،
you'll find that it implies the topic of the examination,
ستجد أنه يتضمن موضوع الفحص ،
which is "Rule the Country by Virtue".
وهو "حكم البلاد بالفضيلة".
(Rule the Country by Virtue)
(حكم البلاد بالفضيلة)
I didn't expect
لم أتوقع
Mr. Jinghu
السيد جينغو
to hide the message so well.
لإخفاء الرسالة جيدًا.
I heard from Chen Chou
سمعت من تشن تشو
that Chen Zishang made money as a ghostwriter.
أن Chen Zishang كسب المال ككاتب شبح.
I guess
اعتقد
(Suzhou Government, Jiangnan County) Ma Lian was informed of the topic in advance
(حكومة سوتشو ، مقاطعة جيانغنان) أُبلغ ما ليان بالموضوع مقدمًا
and paid Chen Zishang to write an essay.
ودفع لـ Chen Zishang لكتابة مقال.
The draft
المسودة
is the evidence that Ma Lian cheated in the examination.
هو الدليل على أن ما ليان خدع في الفحص.
(Rule the Country by Virtue)
(حكم البلاد بالفضيلة)
Why didn't you
لماذا لم تفعل
hand over such important evidence to the Court of Judicial Review
تسليم مثل هذه الأدلة الهامة إلى محكمة المراجعة القضائية
instead of coming to me?
بدلا من المجيء الي؟
It concerns the imperial examination.
يتعلق الأمر بالفحص الإمبراطوري.
Mr. Jinghu also got involved in this.
كما شارك السيد جينغو في هذا الأمر.
So,
لذا،
for the sake of justice
في سبيل العدالة
and the history between our fathers,
والتاريخ بين آبائنا ،
I prefer to give it to you.
أنا أفضل أن أعطيها لك.
To this end,
تحقيقا لهذه الغاية،
you got yourself in jail.
لقد وضعت نفسك في السجن.
Well,
حسنًا،
it was just a misdemeanor.
كانت مجرد جنحة.
I talked back to the officer
تحدثت مرة أخرى إلى الضابط
and was charged with
ووجهت إليه تهمة
lawlessness
الفوضى
and put in jail for two days.
ووضعوا في السجن لمدة يومين.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Since Mr. Jinghu
منذ السيد جينغو
was able to predict that "something will be wrong with Guiyou"
كان قادرًا على التنبؤ بأن "شيئًا ما سيكون خطأ في Guiyou"
before the draw,
قبل القرعة ،
it means
هذا يعني
Chen Zishang's death
وفاة تشن زيشانغ
and the leak of the topic have something to do with him.
وتسريب الموضوع له علاقة به.
Maybe we should
ربما يجب علينا
start with these two cases.
ابدأ بهاتين الحالتين.
If we find out the truth,
إذا اكتشفنا الحقيقة ،
we might be able to draw him out.
قد نكون قادرين على استخراجه.
Zhang Ping.
تشانغ بينغ.
I appreciate it
أنا أقدر ذلك
that you came to the prison
بأنك أتيت إلى السجن
to tell me the truth.
ليقول لي الحقيقة.
But
لكن
we're in different positions.
نحن في مواقف مختلفة.
Do you still hate me
هل مازلت تكرهني
for what happened before?
لما حدث من قبل؟
What happened to my father
ماذا حدث لوالدي
is not your fault.
ليس خطؤك.
I won't blame you.
لن ألومك.
But it still
لكنها لا تزال
had something to do with your mother.
كان له علاقة بأمك.
It's hard for me
هذا صعب بالنسبة لي
to be your friend.
ليصبح صديقك.
I understand.
أفهم.
I'll look into it myself.
سوف أنظر في الأمر بنفسي.
Mr. Lan.
السيد.  لان.
The Empress Dowager summons you.
تستدعي الإمبراطورة الأرملة.
Please.
لو سمحت.
As the chief examiner, I should be held responsible
بصفتي كبير الفاحصين ، يجب أن أتحمل المسؤولية
for such a mistake
لمثل هذا الخطأ
during the imperial examination.
خلال الامتحان الإمبراطوري.
But
لكن
Chen Zishang was absent from the examination for no reason.
وتغيب تشن زيشانغ عن الامتحان بدون سبب.
I was worried,
كنت قلقا،
so I sent someone
لذلك أرسلت شخصًا ما
to his residence
إلى مقر إقامته
who found that Chen Zishang
الذي وجد أن تشن Zishang
had been killed the night before the examination.
قُتل في الليلة السابقة للفحص.
The draft found in his room
وجدت المسودة في غرفته
corresponds to the topic drew on the day of the examination,
يتوافق مع الموضوع المرسوم في يوم الامتحان ،
which is "Rule the Country by Virtue".
وهو "حكم البلاد بالفضيلة".
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I was asked by Mr. Lan to acquire
لقد طلب مني السيد لان الحصول عليها
(Rule the Country by Virtue) Ma Lian's answer sheet from Exam Hall.
(حكم البلد بالفضيلة) ورقة إجابة Ma Lian من Exam Hall.
It's exactly
إنه بالضبط
the same
نفس الشيء
as Chen Zishang's essay.
كمقال تشن زيشانغ.
I also
أنا أيضاً
interpreted Mr. Jinghu's prophetic poem
فسر قصيدة السيد جينغو النبوية
during my time in prison
خلال فترة وجودي في السجن
and found that the poem
ووجدت القصيدة
also implies the topic,
يشير أيضًا إلى الموضوع ،
which means
مما يعني
there were fraudulent examination
كان هناك فحص احتيالي
indeed.
بالفعل.
I hope this case can be thoroughly investigated, Your Majesties.
آمل أن يتم التحقيق في هذه القضية بدقة ، أصحاب الجلالة.
Since you're innocent,
بما أنك بريء
you don't have to go to the Court of Judicial Review.
ليس عليك الذهاب إلى محكمة المراجعة القضائية.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
شكرا لك جلالة الملك.
I dare
اتحداك
to ask
يسأل
who should
من يجب ان
take on the case of fraud.
تتولى قضية الاحتيال.
It will be discussed.
سيتم مناقشتها.
Mother.
الأم.
In my opinion,
في رأيي،
it's urgent
انها عاجل
to find out
تجده في الخارج
who is manipulating
من يتلاعب
the imperial examination
الامتحان الإمبراطوري
and killing people lawlessly.
وقتل الناس بلا قانون.
Do you want to make it worse?
هل تريد أن تزيد الأمر سوءًا؟
How would it make the court look
كيف ستجعل المحكمة تبدو
if we admit there were
إذا اعترفنا بوجودها
fraudulent examination?
فحص احتيالي؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I think...
أظن...
Mr. Liu.
السيد.  ليو.
The prophetic poem implies the topic you wrote.
تشير القصيدة النبوية إلى الموضوع الذي كتبته.
If this is to be investigated thoroughly,
إذا كان هذا سيتم التحقيق فيه بدقة ،
you won't be able to get away with it.
لن تكون قادرًا على الإفلات من العقاب.
I'm not afraid of being investigated.
أنا لا أخشى أن يتم التحقيق معي.
I believe that Commandant Wang and Minister Dou
أعتقد أن القائد وانغ والوزير ضو
are not afraid, either.
ليسوا خائفين أيضا.
- I'm not afraid.
- أنا لست خائفا.  - أنا لست خائفا.
But I think
لكنني أعتقد
this matter has provoked much discussion.
أثار هذا الأمر الكثير من النقاش.
We should smooth things over
يجب أن نهدئ الأمور
and save face for the court first.
وحفظ ماء الوجه للمحكمة أولاً.
After it subsides,
بعد أن تهدأ ،
we can take our time to investigate it.
يمكننا أن نأخذ وقتنا في التحقيق فيه.
You...
أنت...
Mother.
الأم.
Ma Lian is the ideal son-in-law of your brother,
ما ليان هو الصهر المثالي لأخيك ،
your niece's future husband.
زوج المستقبل لابنة أختك.
How will it make
كيف ستصنع
the royal family look
نظرة العائلة المالكة
if he is found guilty of cheating and murdering?
إذا أدين بالغش والقتل؟
They might even think
قد يفكرون حتى
we are covering up for them.
نحن نتستر عليهم.
I'm afraid
أنا خائف
it will undermine your prestige.
سوف يقوض مكانتك.
His Majesty is right.
جلالة الملك على حق.
The case must be thoroughly investigated, Your Majesty.
يجب التحقيق في القضية بدقة ، جلالة الملك.
Fine.
بخير.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
let's investigate it thoroughly.
دعونا نتحرى الأمر بدقة.
Those who participated in the imperial examination,
أولئك الذين شاركوا في الامتحان الإمبراطوري ،
including all the officials, question writers,
بما في ذلك جميع المسؤولين وكتاب الأسئلة ،
chief examiners,
رئيس الممتحنين ،
and invigilators,
والمراقبين ،
are all suspected
كلها مشتبه بها
and will be confined to their homes.
وسيقتصرون على منازلهم.
They won't be allowed to go out without permission.
لن يُسمح لهم بالخروج بدون إذن.
Mother, you're wise indeed.
أمي ، أنت حكيمة حقًا.
But
لكن
Minister Dou
الوزير ضو
and Commandant Wang
والقائد وانغ
are both question writers.
كلاهما كاتب أسئلة.
The Ministry of Justice should avoid arousing suspicion.
على وزارة العدل تجنب إثارة الشبهات.
Then the case should be handed over to...
ثم يجب تسليم القضية إلى ...
The Court of Judicial Review.
محكمة المراجعة القضائية.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I've been ill lately. I fell lightheaded
لقد كنت مريضا في الآونة الأخيرة.  أصبت بالدوار
and can't even read clearly.
ولا حتى القراءة بوضوح.
I'm too weak to lift a brush.
أنا أضعف من أن أرفع الفرشاة.
If the investigation is delayed because of me,
إذا تأخر التحقيق بسببي ،
I'm afraid it will damage the reputation of our important officials.
أخشى أن يؤدي ذلك إلى الإضرار بسمعة مسؤولينا المهمين.
Are you declining it?
هل ترفضه؟
Do you want me to investigate it?
هل تريد مني التحقيق فيه؟
Your Majesty, please don't be mad.
جلالة الملك ، من فضلك لا تغضب.
I'll obey the order.
سأطيع الأمر.
You can go home.
يمكنك العودة إلى المنزل.
Don't
لا
talk back to an officer again.
تحدث مرة أخرى إلى الضابط.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Sir.
سيد.
You've suffered in prison
لقد عانيت في السجن
over the last few days.
خلال الأيام القليلة الماضية.
I didn't expect
لم أتوقع
the His Majesty would back you
سيدعمك جلالة الملك
in the court today.
في المحكمة اليوم.
Looks like it was His Majesty's intention
يبدو أنها كانت نية صاحب الجلالة
to make me the chief examiner.
ليجعلني رئيس الممتحنين.
I think His Majesty
أعتقد جلالة الملك
read my letter carefully.
اقرأ رسالتي بعناية.
Sir.
سيد.
I heard
سمعت
that Mr. Tao acted quickly this time.
أن السيد تاو تصرف بسرعة هذه المرة.
He has taken Ma Lian into custody.
لقد أخذ ما ليان إلى الحجز.
But Ma Lian is having a great time there.
لكن ما ليان يقضي وقتًا رائعًا هناك.
He is eating well and drinking well.
إنه يأكل جيدًا ويشرب جيدًا.
He hasn't been arraigned yet.
لم يتم استجوابه بعد.
Considering Ma Lian's background,
بالنظر إلى خلفية ما ليان ،
Tao Zhoufeng won't make things difficult for him.
لن يجعل Tao Zhoufeng الأمور صعبة عليه.
It's hard to count on him
من الصعب الاعتماد عليه
to solve the case.
لحل القضية.
What should we do?
ماذا علينا ان نفعل؟
We're not good at investigation.
نحن لا نجيد التحقيق.
Commandant Wang and Mr. Dou
القائد وانغ والسيد دو
are also involved in this.
تشارك أيضًا في هذا.
Mr. Wang needs to avoid arousing suspicion.
السيد وانغ بحاجة إلى تجنب إثارة الشكوك.
How about
ماذا عن
we ask Zhang Ping for help?
نسأل تشانغ بينغ للمساعدة؟
We can't investigate
لا يمكننا التحقيق
without the help of other people?
بدون مساعدة الآخرين؟
Get ready.
إستعد.
We'll go to Exam Hall now.
سنذهب إلى قاعة الامتحانات الآن.
But...
لكن...
But you're also confined to your home by the Empress Dowager's order.
لكنك أيضًا مقيد بمنزلك بأمر من الإمبراطورة Dowager.
How to break out
كيف تندلع
by following the rules?
باتباع القواعد؟
There must be something we need at Exam Hall.
يجب أن يكون هناك شيء نحتاجه في Exam Hall.
I only need to take a look inside.
أنا بحاجة فقط لإلقاء نظرة في الداخل.
I won't spoil the scene.
لن أفسد المشهد.
This is non-negotiable.
هذا غير قابل للتفاوض.
Just leave.
ارحل فقط.
What if I can provide a clue
ماذا لو كان بإمكاني تقديم دليل
that might help?
قد يساعد؟
We don't solve cases. We're just gatekeepers.
نحن لا نحل القضايا.  نحن مجرد حراس.
We don't need your help.
لسنا بحاجة لمساعدتكم.
I'll do whatever you want
سأفعل كل ما تريد
as long as you allow me in.
ما دمت تسمح لي بالدخول.
Well...
حسنًا...
We've been standing here for a while
كنا نقف هنا منذ فترة
and our backs are sore,
وظهرنا مؤلمة ،
but no one has brought us anything to drink.
ولكن لم يجلب لنا أحد شيئًا لنشربه.
Yeah.
نعم.
It's getting dark.
المكان يزداد ظلام.
We haven't eaten.
نحن لم نأكل.
Well,
حسنًا،
why is there no one who can bring us some meat and wine?
لماذا لا يوجد من يحضر لنا بعض اللحم والخمر؟
How about this,
وماذا عن هذا،
you guys go eat and drink.
أنتم يا رفاق تذهبون لتناول الطعام والشراب.
I'll guard the entrance for you.
سأحرس المدخل لك.
You used to work at the Court of Judicial Review.
كنت تعمل في محكمة المراجعة القضائية.
Didn't Mr. Lan
لا السيد لان
teach you anything about
يعلمك أي شيء عنه
bureaucracy?
البيروقراطية؟
(What would I do)
(ما الذي يمكنني فعله)
(if I were Mr. Lan?)
(إذا كنت السيد لان؟)
You want money, right?
تريد المال ، أليس كذلك؟
You...
أنت...
How did you say that out loud?
كيف قلت ذلك بصوت عال؟
It's okay.
لا بأس.
We've known him for a long time.
لقد عرفناه منذ فترة طويلة.
That's all I have.
هذا كل ما لدي.
That's all you have?
هذا كل ما لديك؟
For the two prophecies
من أجل النبوءتين
about Exam Hall and the examination question
حول قاعة الامتحان وسؤال الامتحان
to come true,
لكي تتحقق ،
it must be guaranteed that Chen Zishang
يجب أن نضمن أن تشن Zishang
would draw Guiyou
من شأنه أن يرسم Guiyou
and examination question
وسؤال الفحص
must be drawn to be
يجب رسمها لتكون
Mr. Liu's question.
سؤال السيد ليو.
You mean
أنت تعني
someone tampered with these two things
شخص ما عبث بهذين الأمرين
separately?
بشكل منفصل؟
Sir.
سيد.
There is no one here.
لا يوجد أحد هنا.
Come in.
ادخل.
Yes.
نعم.
Shao Zhi and Ji Wen were in charge of
كان Shao Zhi و Ji Wen مسؤولين عن
drawing lots and keeping exam papers.
سحب القرعة وحفظ أوراق الامتحان.
They are the most suspicious.
هم الأكثر ريبة.
And Mr. Yang who drew the question
والسيد يانغ الذي وجه السؤال
is also suspicious.
هو أيضا مريب.
But the people involved are all confined to their homes
لكن الأشخاص المعنيين جميعهم محصورون في منازلهم
and guarded by the soldiers of the Court of Judicial Review.
ويحرسه جنود محكمة المراجعة القضائية.
We can't get in touch with them.
لا يمكننا الاتصال بهم.
That's why
لهذا
we need to start with the physical evidence.
نحتاج أن نبدأ بالأدلة المادية.
Sir.
سيد.
Is there something wrong with this scroll?
هل هناك شيء خاطئ في هذه اللفافة؟
We are about
نحن على وشك
to turn over our duty. Hurry up.
لتسليم واجبنا.  أسرع - بسرعة.
I just got here.
لقد وصلت للتو هنا.
You only gave us five pennies.
لقد أعطيتنا خمسة بنسات فقط.
Do you expect to stay here til tomorrow?
هل تتوقع البقاء هنا حتى الغد؟
You'll have 15 minutes at most.
سيكون لديك 15 دقيقة على الأكثر.
Sir
سيد
(Exam Paper in the 20th Year of Yongxuan) What's the stain on the seal?
(ورقة الامتحان في السنة العشرين من Yongxuan) ما هي البقعة الموجودة على الختم؟
Mold?
قالب؟
How did the ink
كيف الحبر
get moldy?
تتعفن؟
Do you think the mold
هل تعتقد أن القالب
has something to do with the fraud?
له علاقة بالاحتيال؟
But Mr. Yang was blindfolded when he drew the question.
لكن السيد يانغ كان معصوب العينين عندما وجه السؤال.
How could he see it?
كيف يمكنه رؤيتها؟
I think there wasn't any mold when he drew the question,
أعتقد أنه لم يكن هناك أي قالب عندما رسم السؤال ،
or it must have been noticed
أو لا بد أنه تم ملاحظته
with all these people being there.
مع وجود كل هؤلاء الناس هناك.
But how would the ink
ولكن كيف الحبر
get moldy?
تتعفن؟
It looks like the kind of mold growing on rice and flour.
يبدو مثل نوع العفن الذي ينمو على الأرز والدقيق.
I used to see it all the time when I was little.
اعتدت رؤيته طوال الوقت عندما كنت صغيراً.
Did Mr. Yang touch any rice or flour
هل لمس السيد يانغ أي أرز أو دقيق
and get the mold from it?
والحصول على القالب منه؟
There is nothing else unusual about the scroll.
لا يوجد شيء آخر غير عادي في التمرير.
The mold must be the key to solving the case.
يجب أن يكون القالب هو المفتاح لحل القضية.
But
لكن
how did it was drawn?
كيف تم رسمها؟
If we can't figure this out,
إذا لم نتمكن من معرفة ذلك ،
there is no way to convict anyone
لا توجد طريقة لإدانة أي شخص
just by the mold.
فقط بالقالب.
How would I look into this
كيف سأبحث في هذا
if I were Zhang Ping?
لو كنت تشانغ بينغ؟
(It's strange.)
(هذا غريب.)
(The bottom of these rocks)
(قاع هذه الصخور)
(wasn't washed by rain.)
(لم يغسلها المطر.)
(It should be dirty.)
(يجب أن تكون متسخة.)
(Why is this rock the only one with a clean bottom?)
(لماذا هذه الصخرة هي الوحيدة ذات القاع النظيف؟)
(It looks like someone rinsed it on purpose)
(يبدو أن شخصًا ما شطفه عن قصد)
(and put it back.)
(وأعده.)
(There are footprints.)
(هناك آثار أقدام.)
This could be
قد يكون هذا
the primary crime scene.
مسرح الجريمة الأساسي.
Dogs are more capable than you.
الكلاب أكثر قدرة منك.
Get the carriage here now!
احصل على العربة هنا الآن!
Yes, yes.
نعم نعم.
Yes.
نعم.
=A League of Nobleman=
= عصبة النبلاء =